Luis Miguel Del Gallego Horta

Lead Software Engineer / Sr. Software Engineer

Imdelgallego@amail.com | LinkedIn | +573004523529 | Barranquilla, COLOMBIA

Professional Summary

Player-Coach software engineer with 13+ years of experience in software, web and systems development in diverse industries such as Applications, Bank, SaaS, PaaS, Media & Publishing and Advertising. Goal-oriented professional that looks to innovate while finding the right balance between product features and viability and thus becoming the defacto chief viability leader in the development team. Technical leader with a strong background in frontend development, agile methodologies, bug fixing, and adhering to software development standards, at the same time that exhibits leadership skills based on communication abilities and a philosophy of influencing and helping team members and not leaving anyone behind.

Management Qualifications

- Webpack
- Storybooks
- Ionic Framework
- Software development
- Code debugging
- Plan Agile sprints
- Angular
- React
- Git
- Vue

- Design software
- Agile Process
- Creative thinking
- Project Management
- Agile methodologies
- Continuous improvement
- Understanding product lifecycle
- Coach/Mentor
- Self-learner
- Unleash talent

Experience

Player-Coach Sr. Software Engineer Playvox - Manizales, Colombia

Technologies: Docker, Python, Node.Js, Vue, TypeScript, Storybook, CI/CD, Linux

- Worked with Software Development and Testing Team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- Worked in an Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources, helping TL and PO to assign and estimate tasks for spring
- Managed full-cycle design tasks, handling phases from conception to completion while maintaining guidelines throughout
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements
- Collaborated with coworkers to make a template for future developers to use
- Collaborated with Ui/Ux Team to make components for Design System.
- Created process and led the implementation of micro-frontend architecture using module federation on VUE.

Lead Front End Engineer ADL Digital Lab - Bogota, Colombia

Nov 2018 - Oct 2021

Oct 2021 - June 2023

Technologies: Node. Js, Angular, Ionic, TypeScript, JavaScript, Storybook, Jenkins

- Transformed customer culture to an 80% digital culture
- Reviewed and tested customer-facing prototypes before deployment, applying best practice diagnostic techniques to verify usability
- Integrated regulatory and compliance standards into product designs
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI designs
- Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets
- Transformed native applications into mobile-friendly products using Angular9+ for web apps and Angular9+ and Ionic 5 for mobile apps from scratch

Sr. Web UI Developer

Globant - Medellin, Colombia

Technologies: Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript

- Developed new user-facing features, built reusable code and developed libraries for repeat use.
- Integrated APIs and application code and create web applications based on project specifications.
- Designed interfaces, data handling procedures and workflows throughout the application development lifecycle.

Senior Frontend Developer

Sep 2015 - Jun 2018

Jun 2018 - Nov 2018

Ideaware - Barranquilla, Colombia

Technologies: Node.js, Angular, Html, CSS, Sass, PHP, WordPress, TypeScript

- Collaborate with the design and development teams to create clean and elegant interfaces while maintaining an intuitive and concise UX
- Build out prototypes on HTML5 taking special care of representing exactly the provided design
- Research and learn the technologies and methods necessary to meet project objectives
- Participate actively in discussions, presentations and decisions about the development of products.
- Create and implement a 3D interface with ThreeJs and Angular.

Web Developer

Jun 2012 - Aug 2015

Sonovista Publicidad S.A - Barranquilla, Colombia

Technologies: .NET, JSF, PHP, JavaScript, Java, Flash (ActionScripts 2), MySQL

Software Engineer

Mar 2012 - Jul 2012

Serfinansa S.A - Barranquilla, Colombia

Technologies: .NET, JSF, PHP, Java, Flash (ActionScripts 2)

Systems Engineer

Apr 2011 - Feb 2012

Sonovista Publicidad S.A - Barranquilla, Colombia

Technologies: HTML, CSS, .NET, JSF, PHP, Java, Flash (ActionScripts 2)

Web Developer

Nov 2007 - Oct 2011

My Soccer Uniform - Miami, FL, USA

Technologies: PHP, Java, Flash

Software Engineer

Jan 2011 - Apr 2011

Sonovista Publicidad S.A - Barranquilla, Colombia

Technologies: Html, CSS, Flash, PHP, MySQL

Web Developer

Nov 2010 - Feb 2011

Asesorías IT / Caribe Digital - Barranquilla, Colombia

Technologies: HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL

Web Developer

Jun 2006 - Nov 2007

Studio Gráfico/ Miami Graphic - Barranquilla, Colombia

Education

Bachelor of Science: Software Engineer Universidad Autónoma Del Caribe - Barranquilla, Colombia Nov 2011